If you want any tickets,
如果你想买票
you'll have to go round to the front of...
你应该走前面
Well, I suppose it'll be alright.
哦，我想这样也可以
What the hell am I doing around here?
我是在这儿干什么呀？
They walk in here and...
他们走进来还要
Let's see. I hope I got...
让我看看，我希望我有
Three?
三张？
That'll be seven dollars...
七美元
..and 50 cents.
五十分
《西部往事》
No.
别
Frank?
弗兰克？
Frank sent us.
弗兰克叫我们来
Did you bring a horse for me?
你们给我带马来了吗？
Well, looks like we're...
好啊，看起来我们
Looks like we're shy of one horse.
看起来我们不好意思只带一匹来
You brought two too many.
你带两匹来太多了
Pa!
爸！
Look!
看！
That's enough for now. It's getting late. Come on home.
够了，时候不早了 回家去
Timmy.
提米
Maureen, look.
穆琳，看哪
What you doing there?
你在这里干嘛？
Go inside, quick, and get washed.
进屋去，快，去洗一下
And don't touch the apple pie or the roast.
不要碰苹果派和烤肉
Patrick's already left for the station.
帕特里克已经出发去火车站了
He's getting ready, Pa.
他刚刚准备好，爸
- Damn it, Patrick! - Coming, Pa.
- 快点，帕特里克！ - 来了，爸
Not bad, I'd say.
不得不说，还不错
Bigger, them slices. What the hell? We're throwing a party, ain't we?
大些，那些片。怎么回事？ 我们是在准备宴会，不是吗？
But these are the same slices as usual.
但是这些和以前的一样
Yeah, sure.
是的，当然
As usual.
和以前一样
Maureen.
穆琳
Soon, you can cut the bread in slices as big as a door if you want to.
过不了不久，如果你愿意 你可以把面包切的和门一样大
You'll have beautiful new clothes
你会有漂亮的新衣服
and you won't have to work no more.
再也不用干活了
We're going to get rich, Pa?
我们要变富了吗，爸？
Who knows?
天知道？
Patrick!
帕特里克！
Wait a minute!
等一等！
Look at the filth on your boots. Clean 'em.
看看你靴子上的脏东西，去弄干净
The train'll come in and there won't be no one to meet your mother.
火车就要到了，不想没有人接你妈吧
Our mother died six years ago.
我妈六年前就死了
Go now, or you'll really be late.
快走，否则你真的要迟了
Just a minute. Listen, Pa. How will I recognise her?
嗨，等一下，爸 我怎么认出来她
You can't make no mistake, Patrick.
你绝不会认错的，帕特里克
She's young and she's pretty and she's a lady.
她年轻漂亮，并且是位女士
"For travelling, I'll be wearing a black dress
“旅行中，我会穿一件黑衣服
and the same straw hat that I was wearing when we met."
头戴认识你时的那顶帽子。”
I'm gonna get some fresh water from the well.
我去井里打点水来
Oh, Danny boy
噢，丹尼男孩 [爱尔兰民歌：丹尼男孩]
The pipes, the pipes are calling
笛声正在呼唤
And down the mountain side
越过峡谷下到山腰
The summer's gone
夏日已经过去
And all the roses fall...
花儿都已凋谢
Maureen!
穆琳！
What are we gonna do with this one, Frank?
这一个怎么办，弗兰克？
Now that you've called me by name...
现在你都已经叫出我的名字了
- I saw some fine stock down south. - That so?
- 在南面我看到一些优质原料 - 是吗？
And the prices are good.
价格也很公道
- These your valises, ma'am? - Yes.
- 这些是你的行李吗，女士？ - 是的
- Come, Sarah. - Bring them other two.
- 过来，莎拉 - 拿另外两个
We'll tote 'em for you, ma'am.
我们帮你背，女士
Is that true? The sawmill needs hands?
真的吗？ 锯木厂真的需要帮手？
- Was yesterday. - Why didn't you tell your brother?
- 昨天还找人去 - 为什么不告诉你兄弟？
- Hiya, Gramps. - Hiya, Bill. We're back again.
- 嗨，老爷子 - 嗨，比尔，我们又回来了
Come on. Get a move on, will you?
来吧，还不快点，你？
Get the lead out of your asses, you redskin warriors.
快去找你们的头儿 你们这些红皮肤的战士们
I got a whole train to unload.
我还有一整车的货要卸
Alright, chuck down those feed sacks first.
好了 先把那些饲料袋扔下来
Come on!
快点！
What's the name of the place you wanted to go?
你要去什么地方？
Sweetwater.
甜水镇
Brett McBain's farm.
布赖特.马克贝恩的农场
McBain? Yeah, sure.
马克贝恩？噢，是吗
That stubborn redheaded Irishman,
那个顽固的红头发爱尔兰人
tilling sand for years out in the middle of nowhere.
在荒无人烟的沙漠中央耕种沙子
Sweetwater! Only a loony like him
甜水！只有他那样的疯子
could call that stinking piece of desert Sweetwater.
才把那块地上不长毛的沙漠叫作甜水
Sweetwater!
甜水！
A little more to the right.
往右边来一点
Higher.
高一点
Hold it there.
那儿正好
Here they are. Even got here with their damn rails.
这些家伙 把铁路铺到这里来了
They caught up with us again, eh, Lafayette? Let's go!
他们又赶上我们了 架，拉斐德？我们走！
Slow down. What's the matter with you?
慢一点 你怎么搞的？
Watch out down there!
那边的闪一闪！
Slow down!
慢一点！
Why are we stopping? I told you I was in a hurry.
为什么停下？ 我说过我很着急
Don't the train stop?
火车不是也要停吗？
What can I do for you, ma'am?
能为您做点什么，女士？
I would like some water, if it's no trouble.
如果不介意的话 我想要点水
Water? That word is poison around these parts
水？在这里那个词好比毒药
ever since the days of the great flood.
自从那场大洪水后
- You mean you never wash? - We sure do!
- 你是说你们从来不洗澡？ - 当然我们洗！
I'd like to use the same facilities you people do.
我愿意用你们用的相同的东西
You sure can. Just happen to have a full tub at the back.
当然你可以 后面正好有一个装满的浴缸
You're lucky. Only three people have used it this morning.
你很幸运 今天早上才有三个人用过
Used it one at a time or all together?
一个一个用的还是一起？
I can tell you're accustomed to fine living.
我敢说你过惯了舒适的生活
Bet you come from one of those big eastern cities.
你一定是从东部某个大城市来的吧
- New Orleans. - New Orleans!
- 新奥尔良 - 新奥尔良！
- You've been there? - No.
- 你去过？ - 没
But I got a cousin down there. She runs a bar.
但是我有个表姊在那儿 她开了个酒吧
You know, she...
知道么，她
Jug.
一整瓶
Do you only know how to play or do you know how to shoot?
你只知道怎么演奏 还是知道怎么开枪？
Do you know how to blow music from that?
知道怎么用那个吹曲子吗？
Pick it up.
捡起来
You!
你！
You don't know how to play.
你不会玩
Try this one.
试试这个
Take it.
拿着
Go on.
快点
Here.
这儿
Bravo.
做得好
Cheyenne. We thought we'd never make it.
夏恩 还以为我们赶不及呢
It's alright. You're right on time.
还行，你们很准时
To bury my escort.
把那个护卫埋了
If I'd waited for you, I'd be in jail by now.
如果等你 我现在已经在监狱里了
The gun.
我的枪
You interested in fashions, Harmonica?
你很赶时髦，口琴家？
I saw three of these dusters a short time ago.
不久之前我看到三件这样的外套
They were waiting for a train.
在等一列火车
Inside the dusters, there were three men.
三个穿这种外套的家伙
So?
然后呢？
Inside the men, there were three bullets.
每个人身体里都有一颗子弹
That's a crazy story, Harmonica.
骗人的故事，口琴家
For two reasons.
两个原因
One, nobody around these parts
第一个，这里没有人
got the guts to wear those dusters except Cheyenne's, man.
敢穿这种外套 除了夏恩的人
Two, Cheyenne's, man, don't get killed.
第二个，夏恩的人 不会被杀
That surprise you?
你吃惊了吗？
Yeah.
是的
Well, you know music.
哦，你懂音乐
And you can count. All the way up to two.
还能把所有的东西数到二
All the way up to six, if I have to.
数到六，如果我必须
And maybe faster than you.
也许要比你快
Yeah, go on.
好，继续
Play, Harmonica.
吹吧，口琴家
Play, so you can't bullshit.
吹吧，就不会胡言乱语了
Only, watch those false notes.
但是，小心那些错误的注解
Like so?
比如？
This cousin of mine keeps writing me to come down to New Orleans.
我的这个表姊总是写信邀请我去新奥尔良
"Come on down. Help me with the bar. Make a pile of money."
“过来吧，帮我照料酒吧，多挣点钱”
I don't think I'd get along in a big city.
我想我适应不了大城市的生活
It's too full of fast men and loose women.
到处是放荡的男人和女人
Begging your pardon, ma'am. No.
对不起，女士。不
Now, I'm too used to a quiet simple country life.
现在我习惯了安静简单的乡下生活
He's Timmy.
他是提米
Yes.
是的
Dear God.
天哪
On the day...
那天
On the very day of your wedding.
在你婚礼的那天
Poor little miss.
可怜的小姐
Mrs.
夫人
Mrs McBain.
马克贝恩夫人
But we all... We thought...
但是我们都我们以为
I know.
我知道
It was to be a surprise today.
今天你们一定很吃惊
Brett McBain and I were married.
布赖特.马克贝恩和我结了婚
A month ago.
一个月之前
In New Orleans.
在新奥尔良
I am the resurrection and the life.
复活在我，生命也在我
He who believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.
信我的人，虽然死了，也必复活
Whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Amen.
凡活着信我的人，必永远不死。阿门
- Mr Bennett! - What's he doing here?
- 贝奈特先生！ - 他在这里做什么？
I found this collar on a nail by the door.
我发现这个衣领，钉在门上
You got no way of knowing, but this is as good as a signature.
你没办法知道 但这是个最好的签名
Cheyenne's hand.
夏恩的手下
- But why? - Don't worry, Mrs McBain.
- 但是为什么？ - 别着急，马克贝恩女士
We'll make 'em tell us before we hang 'em.
在绞死他们之前，我们会让他们说的
Let's get moving.
我们走吧
Come on. Let's go back to Flagstone.
走吧 我们回石板镇吧
No, Sam.
不，山姆
You go back.
你回去吧
You don't want to stay out here alone.
你不会想一个人留在这里吧
Why not?
为什么不呢？
This is my home.
这是我的家
You know, Wobbles,...
知道吗，无赖
..I'm kinda mad at you.
你让我发火了
Frank wasn't there.
弗兰克不在那儿
He sent three friends.
他叫了三个朋友去
I don't know nothing, I swear.
我什么都不知道，我发誓
I only arranged the meeting the way you wanted it.
我只是按你的意思安排了那个会面
I don't know why Frank wasn't there.
我不知道为什么弗兰克没去
- I swear to you that l... - Cos he was at the McBains'.
- 我对你发誓我 - 因为他在马克贝恩家
That's not true. Cheyenne did that job.
不是他 那是夏恩做的
Everyone knows that. We got proof.
每个人都知道，我们有证据
That was always one of Frank's tricks. Faking evidence.
那不过是弗兰克玩的把戏，捏造证据
I don't know. I swear.
我不知道，我发誓
I only arranged the meeting. I swear.
我只是安排了会面，我发誓
I don't know nothing.
我什么都不知道
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
Did you make coffee?
你会做咖啡吗？
Make it.
去做
Didn't sleep a wink.
一晚上没合眼
A pack of turds dressed in black rode herd on me the whole damn night.
一群黑衣服的卑鄙小人追了我整整一夜
Yeah, but I left them in the middle of the desert.
是的，不过我把他们甩到沙漠里了
If they're lucky, they'll be home in three days.
幸运的话，他们三天后会回来
I'll do it. You fetch the coffee.
我做这个。你去拿咖啡
They want to hang me, the big black crows.
他们想绞死我 那些黑乌鸦
Idiots.
白痴
What the hell?
为什么？
I'll kill anything, but never a kid.
我会杀任何人，但是决不包括孩子
Be like killing a priest.
可以去杀神父
A Catholic priest, that is.
一个天主教的神父，仅此而已
Yeah, the world is full of people who hate Cheyenne.
是啊，这个世界上有很多人痛恨夏恩
See, I ain't the mean bastard people make out.
看，我并不是人们所说的那种混蛋
Of course, if somebody had a mind to kill me,...
当然，如果有人想杀我
..it fires me up.
激怒我
And a fired-up Cheyenne...
被激怒了的夏恩
..ain't a nice thing to see.
可不是好惹的
Especially for a lady.
特别是对于一个女士
But you're too smart to make him mad.
但是你很聪明不会去激怒他
So this here's where I was supposed to do all the killing?
这就是那个说我杀了所有人的地方吗？
Yeah.
哼
Don't seem the place is worth a shit.
没看出来哪里值得
Now, if somebody gets dressed up to look like me,...
那么，如果有人打扮得像我一样
..so they can hang this thing around my neck,...
他们就可以把这事扯在我头上
..I don't like it none.
我一点也不喜欢这样
But I can understand it.
但是可以理解
What I don't understand is why.
我不明白的是为了什么
Neither do l.
我也不明白
But I see you looked a lot for the why.
但是我觉得你知道的很多
Yeah.
没错
What if there were a whole heap of whys?
如果有一整堆问题呢？
Round. Yellow.
圆的，黄的（形容各种豆子）
You know the kind.
你知道的
You rap 'em on a stone,...
你把他们扔到石头上
..and they go "ding".
他们噼啪作响
Maybe.
也许
But I didn't find them.
但是我还没有找到他们
By the way,
顺便问一下
you know anything about a man going around playing a harmonica?
你知不知道一个到处吹口琴的家伙
He's somebody you'd remember.
你应该记住他
Instead of talking, he plays.
他不说话而吹口琴
And when he'd better play, he talks.
当他应该吹的时候，他却说话
You know, when you've killed four, it's easy to make it five.
你明白，如果你已经杀了四个 很容易再有第五个
Sure. You're an expert.
确实如此，你是个行家
Ma'am, it seems to me you ain't caught the idea.
夫人，看起来你没有理解我的意思
Of course I have.
我当然明白
I'm here alone in the hands of a bandit who smelled money.
我孤零零一个人 落在一伙见钱眼开的强盗手里
If you want to, you can lay me over the table and amuse yourself.
如果你愿意，你可以凌辱我寻开心
And even call in your men.
甚或叫你的人进来
Well, no woman ever died from that.
没关系，没有女人因为那样而死
When you're finished, all I'll need will be a tub of boiling water,
你完事后，我需要的仅仅是一盆开水
and I'll be exactly what I was before.
然后我会和以前完全一样
With just another filthy memory.
不过是又多了一个肮脏的回忆而已
You make good coffee, at least.
你的咖啡还不错
Not bad.
不错
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Tell me, was it necessary that you kill all of them?
告诉我，有没有必要把他们全部杀掉？
I only told you to scare them.
我只是告诉你吓吓他们
People scare better when they're dying.
当他们死亡的时候是最恐惧的时候
And can you tell me what good was your stupid massacre?
你能说说你的屠杀有什么好处吗？
Now, a Mrs McBain has turned up.
现在，出来了一个马克贝恩夫人
So, I didn't expect that. It happens in business.
我没有料到那个 是个意外
Let's say this is something I didn't plan on.
这么说吧这是我们没有计划到的
I have no time for surprises, Frank.
我没有时间去吃惊了，弗兰克
You know that.
你知道
I got on board in sight of the Atlantic,
我要上船去看一看大西洋
and before my eyes rot,
在我的眼睛瞎掉之前
I want to see the blue of the Pacific outside that window.
我想看看窗外蓝色的大西洋
I know where you got on board.
我知道你在哪里上火车的
I was there, too, remember.
别忘了，我也在那里
To remove small obstacles from the track, you said.
清除掉道路上的障碍，你说过
Well, there were a few.
哦，还有一些
But we travelled a long way, just the same.
但是我们走了很远 还是一样
And fast.
而且很快
Even tuberculosis of the bones travels fast.
骨头上的结核也走得很快
Don't play the sick man with me, Mr Morton.
别把我当病人，莫顿先生
I knew you when you were just barely limping.
你刚刚开始腿瘸我就认识你了
I watch that dry rot rise a little more every day.
我看着你那枯掉的肢体一天天吞噬你
Any normal man'd put a bullet in his brain.
任何一个正常人都会给自己来颗子弹的
But you, you just got a little more hasty.
然而你，只是变得稍微有些急躁
Otherwise you ain't changed any.
别的你一点都没变
I'd say you've changed, Frank.
你变了，弗兰克
A lot.
很多
You used to take care of certain things personally.
你过去总是亲自去做事情
Now, you're keeping in the background.
现在，你要隐藏在幕后
You'll end up giving orders.
你会最终发号施令
It's because, now, I don't want to leave you alone too much.
因为，目前，我不想让你总是一个人
You're gonna need somebody more and more every day to stay near you.
你需要越来越多的人和你在一起
- Like a friend. - Or like a partner.
- 朋友 - 或是同伙
How does it feel sitting behind that desk, Frank?
感觉如何 坐在那个桌子后面，弗兰克？
It's almost like holding a gun.
就像握着一把枪
Only much more powerful.
不过更有威力些
You see, staying with you, l...
你看，和你在一起，我
..I'm beginning to think big, too.
我也变得目光远大了
This McBain business...
这次马克贝恩事件
..has given me ideas.
给了我一个想法
I'm sorry for you, Frank.
什么意思，弗兰克
You're doing your best.
你做的很好
You'll never succeed in becoming like me.
但是你永远无法取得像我一样的成功
Why?
为什么？
Because there are many things you'll never understand.
因为有很多事情你永远都不会不明白
This is one of them.
这就是其中之一
You see, Frank, there are many kinds of weapons.
看，弗兰克，有很多种武器
And the only one that can stop that is this.
唯一能平息这场风波的是它
Now, shall we get back to our little problem?
现在应该回到我们的小麻烦上了吧？
My weapons might look simple to you, Mr Morton,
也许你认为我的武器很简单，莫顿先生
but they can still shoot holes big enough for our little problems.
但它仍旧可以在我们的小麻烦上打个窟窿
Pretty soon the widow McBain won't be a problem no more.
过不了多久 那个马克贝恩寡妇就不会再是个麻烦了
You wake up one morning and say, "World, I know you."
清晨，你醒来说 “世界，我了解你”
"From now on, there are no more surprises."
“从现在开始，不再有惊奇”
And then you happen to meet a man like this,
然后你偶尔碰倒了一个这样的男人
who looked like a good man.
看起来像是一个好男人
Clear eyes, strong hands.
清澈的目光，强壮的臂膀
And he wants to marry you.
他想娶你
Which doesn't happen often.
这种事不常发生
And he says he's rich, too, which doesn't hurt.
他说他还很富有，那并不重要
So you think, "The hell with New Orleans."
所以你想 “见鬼去吧，新奥尔良”
"Now I'll say yes and go live in the country."
“现在我要说愿意还要去乡下生活”
"l wouldn't mind giving him half a dozen kids after all."
“我不介意给她生一群孩子”
"Take care of a house. Do something. What the hell?"
“照料房子，随便做些事情”
Well, God rest your soul, Brett McBain.
唔，愿主使你的灵魂安息吧，布赖特.马克贝恩
Even if he's going to have a job pulling you out of the devil's grip.
就算他需要去使你脱离恶魔的控制
Still, I swear he'd left money around someplace.
我仍旧愿意发誓 他一定在什么地方留下了财产
If you can find it, you're welcome to it.
如果你能发现就归你好了
Mrs McBain goes back to civilisation.
马克贝恩夫人要回文明社会去了
Minus a husband and plus a great future.
少了一个丈夫，却多了一个好前程
You deserve better.
你应该过得更好
The last man who told me that is buried out there.
上一个对我那样说的男人就埋在那儿
You know, Jill, you remind me of my mother.
知道吗，吉儿，你让我想到了我母亲
She was the biggest whore in Alameida
她是Alameida最出名的妓女
and the finest woman that ever lived.
世界上最好的女人
Whoever my father was, for an hour or for a month,...
无论我父亲是谁，一个小时抑或一个月
..he must have been a happy man.
他都一定是个开心的男人
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Cheyenne's right. Once you've killed four, it's easy to make it five.
夏恩是对的。一旦你杀了四个人 很容易再去杀第五个
This isn't the time to leave.
现在还不是走的时候
Give me some water.
给我点水
From the well.
从井里
I like my water fresh.
我喜欢干净的水
When you hear a strange sound, drop to the ground.
如果你听到奇怪的声响，就匐倒在地上
A sound? Like what?
声响？什么声响？
Like that.
就像那样
He not only plays, he can shoot, too.
他不止会吹口琴，还能开枪
Morning, Mrs McBain.
早上好，马克贝恩夫人
- What brings you to town? - Good morning.
- 什么风把你吹到这儿来了？ - 早上好
Maybe you don't remember, but yesterday at the funeral...
也许你不记得了，昨天在葬礼上
I remember very well.
我记得很清楚
Is there something I can do for you?
有什么我可以帮你的吗？
Yes.
是的
See Frank. And tell him I know everything.
去见弗兰克。告诉他我什么都知道了
Why is everybody hounding me about this guy Frank?
为什么么个人都找我打听弗兰克这家伙
I don't know him. I've never heard of him.
我不认识他 我从来都没有听说过这个人
I got my own worries, and all I want is to be left in peace.
我也很苦恼，我想安安稳稳的生活
Tell Frank I want to negotiate with him. Personally.
告诉弗兰克，我想和他谈判，亲自
You were told not to come here for any reason.
告诉过你任何情况都不要来这里
Whatever business you have with Frank, keep it far away from here.
我不管你和弗兰克有什么交易 离这里远一点
I know, but when I heard that woman say she knew everything,
我知道 但是当我听那个女人说他知道一切时
I thought I should come over here and tell you about it.
我觉得我应该来这儿告诉你这些
You never thought it wasn't a trick?
你没有想到会是个圈套吗？
Sure, but you know I'm mighty careful.
当然，但是你知道我非常谨慎
No one could have followed me.
没有人能跟着我
That's the first thing I learned, working for you.
那试我为你工作学到的第一件事
To listen unseen and to watch unheard.
去听看不到的，去看听不到的
You should learn to live as if you didn't exist.
你应该去学习如何仿佛不存在一样生活
You've known me a long time, Frank.
你认识我很长时间了，弗兰克
You know you can trust me.
你知道你可以相信我
Wobbles.
无赖的家伙
How can you trust a man who wears both a belt and suspenders?
谁会相信一个穿着吊带库却系皮带的家伙
The man can't even trust his own pants.
他连自己的裤子都不相信
Let's get out of here.
我们离开这里
The end of the line.
线路的终点
Yeah.
是啊
Get him on board.
带他上来
Tie him up.
捆上他
Wait, Frank.
等一等，弗兰克
I didn't...
我没有
So, nobody followed you?
好啊，没有人跟踪你？
No. You gotta believe me.
没有，你应该相信我
So, this is the way I can trust you.
我只能这样相信你
I can explain. I didn't know that he...
我可以解释 我不知道那家伙
- Get out. - No, Frank.
- 滚出去 - 不，弗兰克
Get out.
滚出去
Frank, wait!
弗兰克，等一下！
I told you to keep quiet.
我告诉你不要出声
Did Logan and Jim take care of the woman?
Logan和吉姆解决掉那个女人了吗？
Someone took care of them.
一些人在处理他们
We found them out at McBain's place.
我们在马克贝恩家附近发现了他们
Stone dead. And the woman was gone.
死了 那个女人不见了
Your friends have a high mortality rate, Frank.
你朋友们的死亡率很高么，弗兰克
First three, then two.
早先的三个，又有两个
So you're the one who makes appointments.
你就是那个约我的家伙
And you're the one who doesn't keep 'em.
你就是那个没有赴约的家伙
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Who are you?
你是谁？
Dave Jenkins.
戴夫.詹金斯
Dave Jenkins is dead a long time ago.
戴夫.詹金斯很久以前就死了
Calder Benson.
卡德.本森
What's your name? Benson's dead, too.
你的名字？ 本森也已经死了
You ought to know better than anyone.
你应该比别人都清楚
You killed 'em.
你杀了他们？
Who are you?
你是谁？
- Who are you, you... - Frank!
- 你到底是谁？你 - 弗兰克！
The woman.
那个女人
We're only losing time.
我们这是在浪费时间
Alright. This time, I'll take care of her personally.
好吧。这次，我要亲自去会一会她
Yeah, it ought to be easy for you.
对啊，这对你来说在容易不过了
Keep him warm for me.
让他在这里暖和暖和
If he gives you any trouble, hit him.
他要是找麻烦，就打他！
Not in the mouth. He's got to talk. And plenty.
不要打嘴 他还要讲话呢， 而且要说很多
Meet me at the Navajo cliff.
在纳瓦霍悬崖等我
Keep an eye on that cripple all the time.
给我好好看着那个跛子
Sure, Frank.
知道了，弗兰克
- See anyone? - No.
- 看到什么人吗？ - 没有
There he is.
就是他
You only know how to shoot?
你只知道怎么开枪？
Or do you know how to cut, too?
你也知道该怎么砍断绳索吧？
You.
嗨，你
Wait a minute.
等一下
Let's have a good look at you.
让我们好好看看你
Mr Choo-Choo.
火车先生（儿语）
It's easy to find you. Bastard.
找到你很容易，你这个混蛋
I don't have to kill you now.
我现在没有必要杀你
You leave a slime behind you like a snail.
你像蜗牛一样留下粘液
Two beautiful shiny rails.
两条美丽的亮闪闪的铁轨
There's another bastard.
还有另外一个混蛋
And he's getting further away every minute.
他离我们越来越远
There it is. What your husband ordered from me.
这就是了 你丈夫给我买的
And seeing as how he paid cash, it all belongs to you.
他付了我现金， 现在都是属于你的了
Oak planks, beech, pine.
橡木，厚木板，榉木，松木
All first-grade lumber.
都是一流的木材
And there's beams and foundation pylons.
还有这些横梁，路基
Ten kegs of nails, 20 barrels of tar, and all these tools.
十桶钉子，二十桶柏油，和所有的工具
Maybe he wanted to enlarge the farmhouse.
也许他需要用这些来扩大农庄
Enlarge the farmhouse?
扩大农庄？
He could have built at least eight of them.
他都可以建八个农庄了
By the way, ma'am,
顺便问一下，女士
McBain also ordered this. Said it was important.
马克贝恩还买了这个，说是很重要
Only it seems he forgot to tell me what he wanted printed on it.
但是他好像忘记告诉我他想在上面刷什么
Station.
车站
How's that again?
你说什么？
I said print "station".
我说了，在上面刷“车站”
Looking for this?
在找这个吗?
I've had enough of your butcher tactics.
我受够了你的屠夫战术
I know that woman is here.
我知道那个女人在这儿
I don't want any more useless killing.
我不希望再有无谓的残杀
I'm ready to make a deal for that land.
我想跟你买那块地
To pay what's necessary.
付给你应得的那份
I don't want to waste any more time.
我不想再浪费任何时间
You've made a big mistake, Morton.
你犯了个大错，莫顿
When you're not on that train, you look like a turtle out of its shell.
当你不在那列火车上的时候 你就像个缩头乌龟一样
Just funny.
真有趣
Poor cripple talking big so nobody'll know how scared you are.
外表可怜的瘸子，还善于吹牛 所以没有人知道你真正的可怕面目
I'm here to make a deal, Frank.
弗兰克，我来这里是跟你做交易的
I don't have time to compete with you.
我没有时间跟你争
Compete?
跟我争？
Why, you... You can't even stand on your own feet by yourself.
为什么？ 你你自己站都站不稳
Is that sufficient to make you feel stronger?
这样足够证明你强壮了吗？
I could squash you like a wormy apple.
我能把你像烂苹果一样压扁
Sure, but you won't do it.
当然，不过你不会那样做
Because it's not to your advantage.
因为那对你没什么好处
Who knows how far you'd have gone with two good legs.
不知道你还能用你那完好的脚走多远
Help him back to the train. Keep your eye on him.
把他带回火车，看着他
Morton. Don't worry about the land.
莫顿 不用担心那块地
If you feel like paying for it, you can pay.
如果你想付钱的话，你可以付
It won't make any difference to you, dealing with the new owner.
不过这对你来说也没有什么区别 去跟新主人说吧
Cheyenne!
夏恩！
There's a square staked out here. It says "water tank".
这里有个方树桩，上面写着“水槽”
Over here, too. Only, it says "post office".
这里也有一个，不过写着“邮局”
And this one says "corral".
这个写着“畜栏”
And this here "church".
这里写着“教堂”
What the hell is this?
这些都他妈的是什么东西？
Can't you see?
你难道看不出来吗？
It's a station.
这是一个火车站
And all around it, a town.
所有围绕它的是一个小镇
Brett McBain's town.
布赖特.马克贝恩的小镇
Was he crazy!
他疯了！
Yeah, in a very special way.
是呀，从某个特定的角度说
An lrishman.
一个爱尔兰人
He knew that railroad coming through Flagstone would continue on west.
他知道经过石板镇的铁路会继续往西去
So he looked over all this country out here
所以他研究了全国的情况来到了这里
until he found this hunk of desert.
直到他发现了这片沙漠
Nobody wanted it.
没有人需要它
But he bought it.
但是他却买了下来
Then he tightened his belt, and for years, he waited.
然后缩衣节食的过了很多年，他在等待
Waited for what?
他在等待什么呢？
For the railroad to reach this point.
他在等待铁路修到这里
But how could he be sure the railroad would pass through his property?
可是他是怎么知道铁路一定会经过他的领地？
Them steam engines can't roll without water.
那些蒸汽机，运转离不开水
And the only water for 50 miles west of Flagstone is right here.
在石板镇往西50英里以内 有水的地方只有这里
Under this land.
在这片土地下面
He was no fool, our dead friend.
他不是个傻瓜，我们亲爱的朋友
He was going to sell this piece of desert for its weight in gold.
他打算用这块沙漠换取相同重量的金子
You don't sell the dream of a lifetime.
你不会卖掉你毕生的梦想
Brett McBain wanted his station.
布赖特.马克贝恩只是想要他的车站
He got the rights to build it.
他有权利建造它
- How do you know all this? - I saw a document.
- 你是怎么知道这些的？ - 我看过一份文件
It was all in order. Seals, signatures, everything.
一切都井井有条 图章，签字，所有一切
One thing, though.
只有一件东西
In very small print, there is a short clause,
用很小的字写的，是个简短的条款。
which says that McBain or his heirs lose all rights
说马克贝恩或者他的继承人会失去所有的权利
if, by the time the railroad reaches this point,...
如果铁路到达这个地方的时候
..the station ain't built yet.
车站还没有建造好
Speaking of railroads, I noticed the rail gang's already...
说到铁路，我想起了路匪
I noticed the rail gang's already behind those hills.
我注意到路匪早就藏在这些山的后面
And before you know it, they're gonna be here.
在你注意到这点之前，他们就会来到这里
Yeah.
是啊
Listen.
听着
Harmonica.
口琴家
A town built around the railroad.
一个小镇要是建造在铁路附近
You could make a fortune.
你就可以发财了
Hundreds of thousands of dollars.
成百个一千美元
More than that.
或者更多
Thousands of thousands.
成千个一千
They call them millions.
他们说那是上百万
Millions?
上百万？
- Yeah, millions. - Yeah.
- 对，上百万 - 是啊
I always thought it'd be easier to make a deal with a smart lady.
我一直在想 如果跟一个聪明的女士做生意会来得容易些
All you gotta do is...
你所要做的就是
What in the hell are you standing around for?
你们他妈的都一个个杵在这里做什么？
Chief, what are we supposed to do?
头儿，我们应该做什么？
What are you supposed to do?
你们应该做什么？
Build a station, idiots!
建造车站，笨蛋！
I figure it ain't gonna look like much.
我想她不一定会喜欢这个车站
But it'll be the first thing she sees when she gets back.
但是，当她回来的时候 这将是她所看见的第一件东西
If she gets back.
如果她会回来的话
I think...
我想
Yeah.
是啊
I'm beginning to think I might be a little sorry killing you.
我想，如果杀了你的话我会很后悔
You like being alive.
你喜欢活着
You also like to feel a man's hands all over you.
你也喜欢男人的手抚摸你的全身
You like it.
你喜欢这样
Even if they're the hands of the man who killed your husband.
甚至那是杀了你丈夫的那个男人的双手
What a...
啊
What a little tramp.
真是个小骚货
Is there anything in the world you wouldn't do to save your skin?
在这个世界上是不是 没有比保养皮肤更重要的事情了？
Nothing, Frank.
没有了，弗兰克。
Now I understand why they miss you so much...
现在我明白了为什么他们那么想念你
..down there in New Orleans.
在那里，在新奥尔良
Great invention, the telegraph.
伟大的发明，电报
"Jill? The brunette?"
“吉儿？那个深色皮肤的女人？”
"The customers of the most elegant whorehouse on Bourbon Street
“波旁街上妓院里的那个 最有绅士风度的客人
have been weeping ever since she left."
自从她离开了之后，一直伤心哭泣
Say, tell me.
说，告诉我
Did old McBain know?
老马克贝恩知道这些吗？
Yeah.
当然
Yeah, I bet he did.
当然，我打赌他知道
He was just the type to marry a whore.
只有他才是那种跟妓女结婚的人
It's an idea.
我有个好主意
I could marry you.
我可以跟你结婚
And the land would become mine.
不过那块土地要属于我
And maybe...
或许
..you'd make a perfect wife.
或许你能成为一个完美的妻子
It would be me who wouldn't be any good as a husband.
不过我不会是一个好丈夫
Too bad.
太坏了
We'll have to think of another solution.
我们必须另外想出一个解决的办法
Simpler.
更简单
Quicker.
更快捷
As sheriff of this county,
作为本郡的行政长官
I've been asked to preside over the sale by auction
我被邀请主持这次拍卖
of all property belonging to Mrs Jill McBain, here present.
所有属于吉儿.马克贝恩夫人的财产
This parcel of land measures 320 acres.
这片土地总共320英亩
It's free of all encumbrances, liens and mortgages.
没有任何纠纷，留置权和抵押
This property and all it contains,
这块地及其所含
Iock, stock and barrel,
所有的资产
will be turned over to the lucky purchaser at the time of sale.
都将在成交之时过户给幸运的买主
All the contents therein are listed by number
所有的东西都编号排列在
on the inventory sheet distributed among you.
分发给你们的存货表格上
The entire property will be sold in block to the highest bidder.
全部财产将捆绑卖给出价最高的投标人
Alright. That's clear to everybody.
好了。大家都明白了吧
I declare the auction open.
我宣布拍卖开始
Now, who's going to make the first bid?
现在，谁第一个竞拍？
A list of all the items. Some of them are worth money.
所有物品的清单 有些东西还是很值钱的
Alright. Now, who's going to make the first bid?
好了，现在 谁第一个竞拍？
$200.
200美元
Well, I have an opening bid of $200.
好，我们有人出价200美元
$200. Do I hear more?
200美元。有没有更多的？
That stinking piece of land ain't worth it.
那块臭地不值那么多钱
Come on, my friends, $200.
哦，朋友，200美元
The livestock alone is worth twice that much.
那些牲畜就值两倍的价钱
Well...
那么
Who's going to bid $300?
有人出300美元吗？
Now, look, friends, I realise we're not offering California here,
现在，朋友们 我知道我们不是在拍卖加州
but 200 is damn little for all that property.
但是200美元对于这块土地也太少了点
Ladies and gentlemen, I wouldn't even take 200 as a deposit.
女士们，先生们，我不会接受200美元的押金
Well, nobody's going to bid it up.
嗯，没有人再加价了吗？
You're sure you wouldn't want to set a minimum price?
你确信你不需要设一个最低竞价吗？
I wish I were wrong, Mrs McBain,
我希望我是错的，马克贝恩夫人
but you're liable to end up selling the place for a plate of beans.
但是你有义务结束这次拍卖，就算卖得很便宜
All I want is to sell.
我只想把它卖了
- You're fat. - If you say so.
- 你真胖 - 如果你那么说
- How many? - One card.
- 多少？ - 一张牌
One for me.
给我一张
Dealer takes three.
庄家拿三张
Can I take a hand?
我能加入吗？
Yeah, sit down.
行啊，坐下
I'll deal.
我做庄
How do you...
你怎么
How do you play this game, Mr Morton?
你怎么玩法, 莫顿先生
It's very simple.
很简单
As long as you use your head, you never lose.
只要用脑子，你就不会输
$500.
500美元
Do I hear any other bids?
还有没有更高的价钱？
I don't think so.
没有了
I'm sorry, Mrs McBain,
对不起，马克贝恩夫人
but I think I'm gonna have to knock down on that last bid.
但是我想我要最后敲定价钱了
$500 once.
500美元一次
$500 twice.
500美元两次
- $500... - $5,000.
- 500美元 - 5000美元
- You said $5,000? - It's on its way.
- 是你说5000美元吗？ - 他来了
It's Cheyenne!
那是夏恩
The reward for this man is $5,000, that's right?
这个家伙值5000美元赏金，对吗？
Judas was content with $4,970 less.
犹大满足于4,970美元或更少
There were no dollars in them days.
那个时候他们不用美元
But sons of bitches, yeah.
但是他奶奶的，是啊
Wait a minute.
等一下
- The jail's that way. - Yeah, I know.
- 监狱在那边 - 是啊，我知道
Yeah, but you're going to the railroad station.
是啊，但是你在去火车站
I'm sending you to Yuma, Cheyenne.
我要送你去尤马, 夏恩
They got a modern jail there.
那儿有座现代化的监狱
It's got more walls, more bars, more guards.
那里有更多的墙，更多的栅栏 和更多的侍卫
You'll like it, in 20 years. You'll see.
你会喜欢的，在那里20年，你会知道的
Two tickets, amigo, to the next station.
两张票，朋友，去下一站
One way only.
单程
Here's to you. And congratulations.
这是给你的 祝贺你
You got yourself a good deal.
你做了个好买卖
The auction.
拍卖
Forget it. I don't invest in land.
忘了他吧，我没有投资那块地
You don't look at all like the noble defender of poor defenceless widows.
你一点儿也不像个高尚的 保护可怜无助的寡妇的人
But then again,...
不过，也是
..I don't look like a poor defenceless widow.
我也不像一个可怜无助的寡妇
Cheyenne's right. You're a remarkable woman.
夏恩是对的， 你是一个不平常的女人
And you're a remarkable man.
你是一个不平常的男人
But you have something on your mind.
但是你现在已经想到什么了
Have you got something on your mind?
你想到什么了？
Hot water. A bathtub full of hot water.
热水 满满一澡盆热水
I think it's time I filled that bathtub.
我想是时候了 我去放水
Who are you?
你是谁？
Jim Cooper.
吉姆.库珀
Chuck Youngblood.
查克.扬不拉德
More dead men.
多一个死人
They were all alive until they met you, Frank.
要不是遇见了你，他们都还活着，弗兰克
You paid $5,000 for something that belongs to me.
你为那属于我的东西付了5000美元
5,000...
..plus one.
加上一块钱
You've got a right to make a profit, too.
你也有权利得到一点利润
I wouldn't take too long thinking about it, if I were you.
如果我是你的话，我不会想太久
You got yourself into something bigger than you.
你把自己卷入了自己能力之外的事情
You got a chance to get out easy. You better take it.
你现在有机会全身而退，最好收下
You sound like a real businessman, Frank.
你像一个真正的生意人，弗兰克
Being with Mr Morton's done you a lot of good.
跟莫顿先生在一起对你很有帮助
And you've learned some new methods.
而且你还学到一些新方法
Yeah, Mr Morton has shown you a lot of new ways.
是的，莫顿先生教了我很多新的方法
Even though you haven't given up the old ones.
虽然你还没有放弃你的老方法
Pick any method you like. Just make the deal.
任选一种你喜欢的方法 做完这宗买卖
Which deal, Frank?
哪一宗买卖，弗兰克
We have more than one, you and me.
我们不止一宗，你我之间
We can lump them together into one bundle, settle all of them.
我们可以把它们捆在一起，一起解决
Here and now.
就这儿，现在
Easy, Frank.
放松，弗兰克
Easy.
放松
You gotta learn not to push things.
你要学习如何解决问题
Taking it easy is the first thing a businessman should do.
放轻松是一个生意人必须作的第一件事
I got an idea Mr Morton can teach you a lot more.
我有个主意 莫顿先生能教你更多的东西
How much?
多少钱？
One dollar.
一块钱
Giddy up!
驾！
I'd swear we're going to have that strange sound.
我发誓我们会听到那种奇怪的声音
Right now.
现在
Time sure flies.
时间过得真快
It's already past 1 2.
已经过了12点了
But they were his men.
但是他们是他的人
- Yeah. - And they tried to kill him.
- 是啊 - 他们想要杀了他
They found somebody who pays better.
有人出更高的价
And you! You saved his life.
你！你却救了他
I didn't let them kill him. That's not the same thing.
我只是不让他们杀他 那不是一回事
Sure.
对
It's not the same thing.
那不是一回事
You get dressed.
你快穿好衣服
It's time to go home.
是时候回家了
Did you make coffee?
煮咖啡了吗？
This time I did.
这次我煮了
Good.
味道很好
My mother used to make coffee this way.
我母亲就是这样煮咖啡的
Hot, strong and good.
热热的，浓浓的，而且味道很好
Cheyenne.
夏恩
What's he waiting for out there?
他在那里等什么？
What's he doing?
他在做什么？
He's whittling on a piece of wood.
他在削一块木头
I got a feeling when he stops whittling,...
我有预感当他削完的时候
..something's gonna happen.
会有什么事情发生
Surprised to see me here?
见到我很吃惊吗？
I knew you'd come.
我知道你会来的
Morton once told me I could never be like him.
莫顿曾经跟我说过 我永远都不会跟他一样
Now I understand why.
现在我知道为什么了
Wouldn't have bothered him, knowing you were around somewhere alive.
如果没有去找他 你就会知道你还是属于某个地方
So you found out you're not a businessman after all?
所以你发现你根本就不是一个生意人？
Just a man.
只是一个人而已
An ancient race.
一个古老的人种
Other Mortons will be along and they'll kill it off.
其他的莫顿们会过来，他们会把它消灭
The future don't matter to us.
未来跟我们无关
Nothing matters now.
现在也无关
Not the land, not the money, not the woman.
不为土地，不为钱，也不为女人
I came here to see you.
我来这里是要找你
Cos I know that now you'll tell me what you're after.
因为我知道你现在会告诉我你在寻找什么？
Only at the point of dying.
只有在死亡的那一刻
I know.
我知道
I heated some water for you. I also found a razor.
我为你热了一些水，我还找到一个剃刀
Put it there, please.
放在那儿好了
So I can watch the railroad move up while I shave.
我可以在剃胡子的时候看着到火车开过来
You know what?
你知道吗？
If I was you, I'd go down there and give those boys a drink.
如果我是你，我就会下去给那些人一些水喝
You can't imagine
你不能想象
how happy it makes a man to see a woman like you.
能看到你这样的女人会让男人有多么高兴
Just to look at her.
只是看着她
And if one of them should pat your behind,...
如果其中有人在后面拍你
..just make believe it's nothing.
就装作什么都没有
They earned it.
他们值得那个
Keep your loving brother happy.
让你亲爱的兄弟高兴
Who are you?
你是谁？
You're sort of a handsome man.
你是个英俊的男人
But I'm not the right man.
但是我不是那个人
And neither is he.
他也不是
Maybe not.
或许不是
But it doesn't matter.
但是那不重要了
You don't understand, Jill.
你不明白，吉儿
People like that have something inside.
那样的人总是有些东西藏在心里
Something to do with death.
一些跟死亡有关的东西
If that fella lives, he'll come in through that door,
如果那个家伙还活着，他会从那扇门进来
pick up his gear and say adios.
拿起他的行李说再见
It would be nice to see this town grow.
能看到这个小镇建成真得很好
Now I gotta go.
现在我要走了
Gonna be a beautiful town, Sweetwater.
这里将成为一个美丽的小镇，甜水
I hope you'll come back someday.
我希望你将来能回来
Someday.
将来
Yeah. I gotta go, too.
是啊，我也要走了
Make believe it's nothing.
让人们相信什么都没有发生过
Sorry, Harmonica.
对不起，口琴家
I gotta stay here.
我要留在这里了
Who?
谁干的？
I ran into Mr Choo-Choo.
我遇到了火车先生
I didn't count on that half-man from the train.
我没有考虑到火车上那个废人
He got scared.
他看起来很害怕
Harmonica.
口琴家
When they do you in,
当他们射中你的时候
pray it's somebody who knows where to shoot.
真希望那家伙知道该往哪儿打
Go away.
走开
Go away. I don't want you to see me die.
走开 我不希望你看着我死